Finding Aid for the Women in Animation Oral Histories and Records PASC.0222
UCLA Library Special Collections
Women in Animation oral histories and records
1994-1997
UCLA Library Special Collections
Women in Animation
PASC.0222
8.6 linear feet (22 boxes)
17 audiovisual carriers (17 cassettes)
9 audiovisual carriers (9 unprocessed videocassettes)
17 born-digital carriers (10 unprocessed optical discs, 6 unprocessed floppy disks, 1 unprocessed hard drive)
Women in Animation (now WIA) was created in 1993 to support the small number of women in the field of animation through community building and professional networking opportunities. The collection consists of oral history transcripts from interviews conducted by the organization, Women in Animation, and its business records.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
CONTAINS DIGITAL AND AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS: This collection contains both processed and unprocessed digital and audiovisual materials. For information about the access status of the material that you are looking for, refer to the Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note at the series and file levels. All requests to access processed digital and audiovisual materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Women in Animation, Inc., 1999.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9944361793606533
Biographical / Historical
Women in Animation (now WIA) was created in 1993 to support the small number of women in the field of animation through community building and professional networking opportunities. Since then, WIA has evolved into the advocacy group supporting female- identifying and non-binary people in animation, visual effects, and gaming, and includes over 11,000 members worldwide.
Description from Women in Animation website, accessed July 2024.
Scope and Contents
Collection consists of oral history transcripts from interviews conducted by the organization, Women in Animation, and its business records. Contains interviews with women pioneers from the animation industry, including Frances Arriola, Susan Ashley, Barbara Baldwin, Betty Brooks, Martha Buckley, Xenia De Mattia, Becky Fallberg, Mary Jane Frost, Grace Godino, Wilma Guenot, Julie Harvey, Anneline Liu, Joan Orbison, Sylvia Roemer, Martha Sigall, Gini Swift and Auril Thompson. The interviews are varied in terms of positions held and talents expressed while in the animation industry.
Arrangement
This collection has been arranged in the following series:
Series 1: Oral histories
Series 2: Records
- Series 1: Oral histories
  - Transcripts, 1994-1997 (Box 1, Folder 1-17)
  - Cassette recordings, 1994-1997; 17 audiovisual carriers (17 cassettes) (Box 2)
    General
    These 17 cassettes have been digitized and can be found \avpres\LSC\PASC\WomenInAnimation_pasc_222
    Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
    CONTAINS AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS: Audiovisual materials are available for access. All requests to access digital materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
- Series 2: Records, 9 audiovisual carriers (9 unprocessed videocassettes); 17 born-digital carriers (10 unprocessed optical discs, 6 unprocessed floppy disks, 1 unprocessed hard drive)
  CONTAINS UNPROCESSED DIGITAL AND AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS: Digital and audiovisual materials are not currently available for access and will require further processing and assessment. If you have questions about this material please email AskLSC@library.ucla.edu.
  - Membership Applications, 2003-2005 (Box 3, Folder 1-6)
  - Records, 2002-2003 (Box 4, Folder 1-4)
  - Records, Newsletters, Meetings, 2003-2006, 1994-2005 (Box 5, Folder 1-5)
  - Newsletters, Board Reports, Meetings and Elections, 1994- 2007 (Box 6, Folder 1-11)
  - Meetings, Reports, Mary Cain Travel Items, Papers, 1997-2002 (Box 7, Folder 1-12)
  - BoD Meetings, Reports, Clippings, Photos, 1997-2012 (Box 8, Folder 1-13)
  - Membership Apps, Photos, Records, 1993-1994, 2006 (Box 9, Folder 1-5)
    CONTAINS UNPROCESSED DIGITAL MATERIALS: Digital materials are not currently available for access and will require further processing and assessment. If you have questions about this material please email AskLSC@library.ucla.edu.
    This box contains 6 CDS.
  - Membership List, Records, 1995-1996 (Box 10, Folder 1-4)
  - Records, 1994-1998 (Box 11, Folder 1-5)
  - Records, 1996-1998 (Box 12, Folder 1-4)
  - Membership Lists, Applications, 1996-2008 (Box 13, Folder 1-5)
  - Memorabilia (Box 14)
    Scope and Contents
    3 shirts, 3 mugs, 1 bag
  - Records, Membership Apps, 2002-2012 (Box 15, Folder 1-5)
    This box contains one flash drive.
  - Reports, Correspondence, Flyers, Workshops, 1995- 2005 (Box 16, Folder 1-12)
  - Meetings, Flyers, Events, 1995-1997 (Box 17, Folder 1-10)
    CONTAINS UNPROCESSED AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS: Audiovisual materials are not currently available for access and will require further processing and assessment. If you have questions about this material please email AskLSC@library.ucla.edu.
    This box contains one U-matic.
  - Meetings, Photos, Files, 1994 - 2005 (Box 18)
    CONTAINS UNPROCESSED DIGITAL/AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS: Digital/audiovisual materials are not currently available for access and will require further processing and assessment. If you have questions about this material please email AskLSC@library.ucla.edu.
    This box contains 8 VHSs, 4 CDS, and 6 floppy disks.
  - Membership Applications, 1994-1996 (Box 19, Folder 1-4)
  - Records, 1999 (Box 20, Folder 1-4)
  - Records, 1999-2001 (Box 21, Folder 1-4)
  - Members, meetings, reports, newsletters, 1999-2000 (Box 22, Folder 1-10)